Brandon Reid

Personal Rater I

Address 5 Prospect St

Farmington, NH 03835

Phone 603-973-5334

E-mail brandonreid93@gmail.com

Date of birth 10/29/1993

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/brandon-reid-93874965/

Motivated insurance professional with over three years of experience in customer service and process improvement. Currently pursuing BS in Computer science (12/2019). Proven technical aptitude and ability to quickly learn new and exciting technologies and a drive to continue improving.

Experience

01/2018 - present

Personal Rater I

Liberty Mutual, Production operations

Responsibilities include processing and recording policy changes and change requests for manual policies within the RIS system while adhering to the company guidelines and individual state's requirements. Deep understanding of the California motorcycle manual policy rating system as well as the California auto rating system and the specific requirements the California DMV mandates. Acts as a subject matter expert on manual DMV filings and reports for team members and field support. Provides support for field staff regarding DMV filing questions and concerns as well as verifying knowledge center is up to date. Developed numerous tools and process changes to improve the customer experience by ensuring all error reports are processed correctly and in a timely manner; a combination of VBA, IBM Passport macro's and VBScript was used to create the various tools.

02/2017 - 01/2018

Contractor

Liberty Mutual, Production operations

Originally hired as a contractor on the Dover Loss Avoidance team within production operations to process North Carolina CTR reports using CSW and mail merges. Moved over to the Auto Zone 3 team within Production Operations to assist with DMV error reports and customer service requests for filings. Developed tools to remove redundancies and manual interactions for the various error reports using VBA and AHK scripts.

11/2016 - 01/2017

Inside Sales Executive

Netria Corporation, Sales

Responsible for making outbound calls to establish relationships with purchasing managers at a variety of companies within the northeast area. Once there was an established relationship I was responsible for all aspects of sales from quoting to shipping and ensuring each customer was satisfied with their order.

08/2015 - 11/2016

Collections Specialist

Delta Management Associates, Collections

Responsible for contacting default borrowers on federal student loans (Navient) and educating them on what options they are entitled to resolve the problem and get all their loans back into good standing. Required to make a minimum of 100 outbound calls and a minimum of 90 minutes of recording talk time daily. Additionally I was required to use a variety of tools to identify the borrowers place of employment for possible wage garnishment.

Education

12/2019 Southern New Hampshire University, Computer Science, BS

08/2016 Southern New Hampshire University, Accounting, AS